Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an elementary level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节初级课程。
This is about fixing things.
这节课是关于修理东西的。
That's right.
没错。
So sometimes in our office or in our house, some small things may break like maybe the
有时候在办公室或家里，一些小东西可能会坏掉，比如
door or the air conditioning.
门或者空调。
So in this case, we need to call a special guy to come and fix it.
这种情况下，我们需要叫一个专门的人来修理。
So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment to talk about who this
那么，我们来听今天的对话，稍后回来聊聊这个
guy is.
人是谁。
The air conditioning is not working.
空调坏了。
We need to call a handyman before we start to fry in here.
我们得叫个修理工来，不然这里就要热炸了。
Dan is on top of that.
Dan已经在处理这件事了。
I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom toilet that keeps clogging
我想他们也让修理工去修浴室里那个老是堵塞的
up.
马桶。
That would be convenient.
那倒是挺方便的。
They might as well ask him to fix the electrical wiring.
他们不如让他顺便把电线也修一下。
The circuit breakers keep going out all the time.
断路器老是跳闸。
It's really annoying.
真的很烦人。
Yeah, you're right.
是啊，你说得对。
This office is falling apart.
这间办公室快散架了。
Frank told me the other day that the gutters outside were clogged and that's why the parking
弗兰克前几天告诉我，外面的排水沟堵了，这就是为什么停车场
lot was flooded.
被淹了。
I know.
我知道。
I was in ankle deep water trying to get to my car that day.
那天我踩着深及脚踝的水，好不容易才走到车那儿。
The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
这位杂工肯定有得忙了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of those key words and phrases on Language Takeaway.
现在让我们来看看“语言小贴士”中的一些关键词和短语。
Language Takeaway Our first word today is the name of this
语言小贴士 今天的第一个词是这种
job.
工作的名称。
The person is called a handyman.
这个人被称为杂工。
Okay, so that's a profession.
好的，所以那是一种职业。
You are a handyman.
你是一名杂工。
Now what exactly does a handyman do?
那么杂工具体是做什么的呢？
Well, a handyman fixes things.
嗯，杂工负责修理东西。
He is usually a generalist.
他通常是个多面手。
He fixes things all over the house, not just the bathroom or the kitchen.
他修理房子各处的东西，不只是浴室或厨房。
So he can just fix things that are a little bit broken.
所以他只能修一些有点小毛病的东西。
But if, for example, your car needs a new radiator or it needs a new important part,
但比如，如果你的车需要换新散热器或重要零件，
maybe you would take the car to someone who is more experienced with cars.
你可能会把车送到更有经验的人那里去。
But in the case of a handyman, if anything is broken, he can generally fix it.
但就杂工而言，如果有什么东西坏了，他通常都能修好。
Okay, so as Catherine explained, basically a handyman just does any type or many types
好的，正如凯瑟琳解释的那样，杂工基本上就是做任何类型或多种类型
of general work of things that may be broken around the house or the office.
的普通工作，比如家里或办公室里可能坏了的东西。
We had a couple of examples of these in today's dialogue, didn't we?
今天的对话中有几个这样的例子，对吧？
What was that first one?
第一个是什么？
Kind of gross.
有点恶心。
Yeah, well, he had to fix the air conditioning, but then he also had to fix the bathroom toilet
是啊，他得修空调，但还得修浴室马桶，
because it kept clogging up.
因为它老是堵塞。
Okay, so a toilet gets clogged up.
好的，所以马桶堵塞了。
To clog up.
堵塞。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
So it means that something is blocking the way of the water being able to go out.
意思是有什么东西堵住了水排出去的通道。
So the water doesn't go down.
所以水就下不去了。
And sometimes if the toilet is really clogged and someone tries to flush the toilet again,
有时候如果马桶堵得很厉害，有人再冲一次水，
the water comes onto the floor and it's very dirty and very gross.
水就会流到地上，又脏又恶心。
That's right.
没错。
So actually, maybe sometimes in the kitchen, pieces of food may fall into the sink and
所以实际上，有时候在厨房里，食物残渣可能会掉进水槽，
it may clog up the sink.
导致水槽堵塞。
Okay, so to clog up means to block or to get in the way of.
好的，所以“堵塞”意思是阻塞或挡住路。
That's right.
没错。
And apart from the toilets being clogged up, he also may have to take a look at the circuit
除了马桶堵塞之外，他可能还得检查一下电路
breakers.
断路器。
All right, so this is not about water or about plumbing.
好的，所以这跟水或管道无关。
Circuit breakers have to do with electricity.
断路器跟电有关。
And in this case, that box in your apartment or near your apartment that controls the different
在这种情况下，就是你公寓里或公寓附近那个控制不同
circuits.
电路的电箱。
So sometimes if the lights go out, you know that you have to check the circuit breaker
所以有时候如果灯灭了，你知道得检查断路器
and make sure that the circuits are all working properly.
并确保所有电路都正常工作。
That's right.
没错。
So the circuit breakers are kind of like a protection from too much electricity and that's
所以断路器有点像防止电流过大的保护装置，这就是为什么它们会跳闸。
why they go out.
And now for our final word on language takeaway, something that also got clogged up at their
现在来看我们语言学习的最后一个词，他们办公室也堵了的东西，我们说的是排水沟。
office, we're talking about the gutters.
All right, so many people's houses have gutters or sometimes an office building will have
好的，很多人的房子都有排水沟，有时办公楼也会有
gutters.
排水沟。
These are trays on the roof of a house or a building that will catch the water when
这些是房子或建筑物屋顶上的槽，用来接住下雨时的
it rains.
雨水。
Because you know, sometimes rainwater can be very, very heavy and it's dangerous on
因为你知道，有时雨水会非常非常重，对你的房子、屋顶很危险，因为它会损坏屋顶。
your house, on the roof of your house because it can hurt the roof.
But if it comes into this gutter, into this little tray, then it will come down and fall
但如果雨水流进这个排水沟、这个小槽里，它就会流下来并落下。
on the ground.
在地面上。
So these are a way to protect your roof.
所以这些是保护屋顶的一种方式。
But these often get clogged up with leaves and with garbage.
但这些经常被树叶和垃圾堵塞。
That's right.
没错。
So they're like small little ways or little roads, if you want to call them, where the
所以它们就像小小的通道或小路，如果你愿意这么叫的话，水可以沿着它们流走并进入特定地方。
water can go and escape and go into a specific place.
水可以沿着它们流走并进入特定地方。
We have them on the sides of roads as well, many times.
我们在路边也经常看到它们。
So gutters that you find on the ground, sometimes you find them on the roof of a house, but
所以地面上的排水沟，有时你会在屋顶上找到它们，但那些有点不同。
those are a little bit different.
那些有点不同。
The gutters on the ground are basically pathways for water to come down.
地面上的排水沟基本上是水往下流的通道。
Because if there's no gutter, then all of the water is on the road and it can flood
因为如果没有排水沟，所有的水都会积在路面上，很快就会引发洪水。
very quickly.
很快就会引发洪水。
That's right.
没错。
And so this is a way for the water and even the garbage to go on the side of the road
所以这是一种让水甚至垃圾流到路边的方式。
and not be in the way of the cars.
不会妨碍车辆通行。
That's right.
没错。
You see them on highways and roads very often because you don't want the road filled with
你在高速公路和普通道路上经常看到它们，因为你不希望路面充满水。
water.
水。
So these gutters are a small path where all the water will fall into it and escape safely
所以这些排水沟是一条小通道，所有的水都会流入其中，安全地从高速公路排走。
from the highway.
安全地从高速公路排走。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the time we have for Language Takeaway.
这就是我们“语言要点”环节的全部内容。
Why don't we go back, have another listen to the dialogue and we'll be back soon with
我们不如回去再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来继续“流利度构建”环节。
Fluency Builder.
“流利度构建”环节。
The air conditioning is not working.
空调坏了。
We need to call a handyman before we start to fry in here.
我们得在热死之前叫个修理工来。
Dan is on top of that.
丹已经在处理了。
I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom toilet that keeps clogging
我想他们也让修理工去修浴室里老是堵塞的马桶了。
up.
老是堵塞。
That would be convenient.
那倒挺方便的。
They might as well ask him to fix the electrical wiring.
他们不妨也让他修修电线。
The circuit breakers keep going out all the time.
断路器老是跳闸。
It's really annoying.
真的很烦人。
Yeah, you're right.
是啊，你说得对。
This office is falling apart.
这办公室快散架了。
Frank told me the other day that the gutters outside were clogged and that's why the parking
弗兰克前几天告诉我，外面的排水沟堵了，所以停车场才被淹了。
lot was flooded.
停车场才被淹了。
I know.
我知道。
I was in ankle deep water trying to get to my car that day.
那天我为了走到车那儿，水都淹到脚踝了。
The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
修理工这下可有得忙了。
Now let's take a look at three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在我们来看看“流利度构建”环节的三个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
“流利度构建”环节。
Well, this first phrase is a phrase that I like to use and I do use it very often.
嗯，第一个短语是我喜欢用的，而且我确实经常用。
We heard that Dan is on top of that.
我们听到丹已经在处理了。
We need to call a handyman in here and he says, nope, Dan is on top of that.
我们需要叫个修理工来，然后他说，不，丹已经在处理了。
To be on top of something, what does it mean?
“处理某事”是什么意思？
When she says Dan is on top of that, she's basically saying Dan is taking care of this
当她说丹已经在处理了，她基本上是在说丹正在负责这件事。
or Dan is already calling the handyman to come and fix it.
或者丹已经在叫修理工来修了。
You are aware of the problem and you're trying to solve it.
你意识到了问题，并且正在努力解决它。
Okay, so don't worry.
好的，所以别担心。
You don't have to call the handyman.
你不用叫修理工了。
Dan is on top of that.
丹已经在处理了。
Dan will call him.
丹会叫他的。
Right.
对。
So to be on top of something is to make sure that something is done.
所以“处理某事”就是确保某事被完成。
So you could say, you know, Marco, I really, I hope you stay on top of that project because
所以你可以说，你知道，马可，我真的希望你能跟进那个项目，因为它非常重要。
it's very important.
因为它非常重要。
Right.
对。
Or don't worry, the report will be finished on time.
或者别担心，报告会按时完成的。
I am on top of that.
我正在处理。
Great.
很好。
All right.
好的。
Now moving on to our next phrase, they were talking about all the problems that this office
现在来看下一个短语，他们正在谈论这间办公室的所有问题，然后有人说，他们不妨也让修理工修修电线。
has and the person said, well, they might as well ask the handyman to also fix the electrical
他们不妨也让修理工修修电线。
wiring.
电线。
Okay.
好的。
So this phrase might as well is, it's kind of hard to understand I think sometimes.
所以这个短语“不妨”有时候我觉得有点难理解。
Basically what the speaker is saying is that while he is doing this, he can also do something
基本上，说话者是在说，既然他在做这件事，他也可以顺便做点别的。
else.
也可以顺便做点别的。
Okay.
好的。
So he's here.
所以他在这儿。
He can fix many things.
他可以修很多东西。
He might as well also fix electrical wiring.
他不妨也修修电线。
Right.
对。
So taking advantage of the fact that you are already doing something or you are already
所以利用你已经在做某事或已经在这里的事实，你也可以开始做别的事情。
here, you can start doing something else as well.
你也可以开始做别的事情。
Or maybe we could say this in a different context to like, you know, we're going to
或者我们可以在不同的语境下这样说，比如，你知道，我们午餐要订披萨。
order a pizza for lunch.
我们午餐要订披萨。
You know what, Marco might as well order two because there are so many people here.
你知道吗，马可不妨订两个，因为这里人太多了。
Right.
没错。
So taking advantage of the fact that we are ordering pizza, we might as well get more
所以既然我们正在点披萨，不如多要点
for everyone.
给大家分。
Okay.
好的。
And for our last phrase, when they mentioned all the work that has to be done, they said
至于我们最后一个短语，当他们提到所有需要完成的工作时，他们说
the handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
这位杂工肯定有得忙了。
Okay.
好的。
So if someone has his work cut out for him, it means that he has a lot of work to do.
所以如果某人“has his work cut out for him”，意思是他有很多工作要做。
That's right.
没错。
You can also say this to someone that you're talking to.
你也可以对正在交谈的人说这个。
So Marco, Marco is writing a book.
所以 Marco，Marco 正在写一本书。
I say, Hey Marco, that's a really long book you're writing.
我说，嘿 Marco，你写的这本书真长。
It looks like you really have your work cut out for you.
看起来你真有得忙了。
That's right.
没错。
Or maybe this project is really difficult.
或者也许这个项目非常困难。
I really have my work cut out.
我真是有得忙了。
Okay.
好的。
So you're basically saying I have a very hard time ahead of me.
所以你基本上是在说，我前面有一段很艰难的时间。
Okay.
好的。
So that's all the phrases we have for you.
这就是我们为你准备的所有短语。
Why don't we have a listen to our dialogue one last time.
我们最后再听一遍对话吧。
The air conditioning is not working.
空调坏了。
We need to call a handyman before we start to fry in here.
我们得叫个杂工来，不然这里就要热死人了。
Dan is on top of that.
Dan 在负责这件事。
I think they are also getting the handyman to fix the bathroom toilet that keeps clogging
我想他们也让杂工修一下浴室里老堵的马桶
up.
。
That's really inconvenient.
那真的很不方便。
They might as well ask him to fix the electrical wiring.
他们不如让他也修修电线。
The circuit breakers keep going out all the time.
断路器老是跳闸。
It's really annoying.
真烦人。
Yeah, you're right.
是啊，你说得对。
This office is falling apart.
这办公室快散架了。
Frank told me the other day that the gutters outside were clogged and that's why the parking
Frank 前几天告诉我外面的排水沟堵了，所以停车场
lot was flooded.
被淹了。
I know.
我知道。
I was in ankle deep water trying to get to my car that day.
那天我踩着深及脚踝的水才走到我的车。
The handyman definitely has his work cut out for him.
这位杂工肯定有得忙了。
So a handyman is also commonly referred to as a jack of all trades.
所以杂工也常被称为“万金油”。
That's right.
没错。
So these are both kind of funny words.
这两个词都挺有趣的。
First of all, handy as an adjective means useful or helpful.
首先，“handy”作为形容词意思是有用或有帮助的。
So maybe a hammer is a handy tool.
所以锤子可能是个好用的工具。
It's a very handy tool or I find my iPhone has some very handy applications.
它是个很好用的工具，或者我觉得我的 iPhone 有一些很好用的应用。
I can use the dictionary.
我可以用字典。
So a handyman is someone who's helpful.
所以“handyman”就是有帮助的人。
He can do many things.
他能做很多事情。
But a jack of all trades is very special because it means he is a person that can do basically
但“万金油”很特别，因为它意味着他基本上能做
any job.
任何工作。
Right.
对。
So sometimes in offices, people may have someone that they may refer to as a jack of all trades.
所以有时在办公室里，人们可能有个他们称为“万金油”的人。
So he may fix the computers.
他可能修电脑。
He also knows a little bit about marketing and does many odd and random things around
他也懂一点营销，并在办公室做各种零碎
the office.
的事情。
That's right.
没错。
You could say my friend Paul, he's a jack of all trades.
你可以说我的朋友 Paul，他是个万金油。
He can fix a car.
他能修车。
He can cook.
他会做饭。
He can fix a door or a window, but he can also sew.
他能修门或窗户，但他还会缝纫。
So he's a jack of all trades.
所以他是个万金油。
He has many, many skills.
他有很多很多技能。
That's right.
没错。
And talking about these skills, being a handyman is not a profession per se.
说到这些技能，做杂工本身并不是一个职业。
It's actually a trade.
它实际上是一门手艺。
That's right.
没错。
And so we say this because it's something that you normally do with your hands and you
我们这么说是因为这通常是用手做的事情，而且
don't have to go to university to study it.
你不需要上大学去学。
You maybe have an apprenticeship where you study by working.
你可能通过学徒制边工作边学习。
And it's one of a few very, very important trades like being a plumber or an electrician.
这是少数非常重要的手艺之一，比如水管工或电工。
But a handyman is more general.
但杂工更通用。
Like we said, you can do many different things.
就像我们说的，你能做很多不同的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So very interesting.
所以很有趣。
There are many trades out there.
外面有很多手艺。
Maybe you can come on the site and mention some of these that you may know.
也许你可以来网站上提一些你知道的。
Like for example, a very well known trade is a cobbler, a person that makes shoes.
比如，一个很有名的手艺是鞋匠，做鞋的人。
Makes shoes or fixes shoes.
做鞋或修鞋。
It's a very weird word though because shoes and cobbler don't seem to have much to do
不过这个词挺奇怪的，因为鞋和鞋匠似乎没太大关系
with each other.
。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, many, many, many trades like this.
嗯，很多很多这样的手艺。
I know before they used to be blacksmiths.
我知道以前他们是铁匠。
So many types of trades.
这么多不同的行业。
And of course, if you have any other questions or doubts, you can visit our website EnglishPod.com.
当然，如果你还有其他问题或疑问，可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you guys there.
我们希望能在那儿见到你们。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。